Alice Recknagel Ireys Papers, 1885-2001
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VII. SPEECHES
  - Speeches (chronological listing)
    - Long Island Historical Society, "Gardens Old and New"20 Apr 1975 (Box 104, Folder 63)
    - Rye Garden Club and Little Garden Club of Rye, "Planning a Small Garden"6 Jan 1976 (Box 104, Folder 64)
    - New Canaan (CT) Garden Club, "Planning the Home Grounds with Interesting Plant Material"21 Jan 1976 (Box 104, Folder 65)
    - Staten Island Garden Club, "Planning Small Gardens"24 Mar 1976 (Box 104, Folder 66)
    - Garden Club of Darien (CT), "Planning Small Gardens"18 May 1976 (Box 104, Folder 67)
    - Bridgewater (MA) Garden Club, "Planning a Small Garden"27 Oct 1976 (Box 104, Folder 68)
    - Brooklyn Heights Garden Club, "How to Write a Book on City Gardens"17 Jan 1977 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - North County Garden Club of Long Island, "A Water Feature in Your Garden"2 Mar 1977 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Cohasset (MA) Garden Club, "Renovating a Property"15 Jun 1977 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Colony Club series "Ten Reasons to Plant Bulbs"13 Oct 1977; "Ideas for Special Features," 26 Jan 1978; and "Unusual Plants for City and Country Gardens," 9 Mar 1978 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden Symposium, "Gardening in Containers"12 Feb 1978 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Remsenburg (NY) Garden Club, "Planting a Garden Near the Sea"15 Jun 1978 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - East Hampton (NY) Garden Club, "Planning a Small Garden with Year Round Interest"5 Dec 1978 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Three Harbors Garden Club (NY), "Landscape Ideas for Small Gardens"5 Mar 1979 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Garden City Historical Society, "Victorian Gardens"18 Mar 1979 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Old Westbury Gardens, "History of Garden Design"15 Jun 1979 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Clark Memorial Garden, 10th Anniversary of Clark Garden29 Sep 1979 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Central Connecticut Packer Alumni, "Gardens for Grandparents"22 Oct 1979 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Garden City Historical Society, "Evergreens for Gardens Old and New"14 Nov 1979 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - City Gardens Club (NYC), "Evergreens for City and Country Gardens"26 Nov 1979 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Sands Point (NY) Garden Club, "Evergreen Plantings for Terraces and Decks"4 Feb 1980 (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Matinecock Garden Club, "Landscape Ideas for the Home Grounds"11 Mar 1980 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Alfred T. White Memorial Lecture, "The Joys of Gardening for One and All"5 Oct 1980 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Chevy Chase (MD) Garden Club, "Landscape Ideas for Small Gardens"20 Oct 1980 (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Ireys home, "Planning Your City Garden"13 and 20 Mar 1981 (Box 105, Folder 19)
    - Herb Society of America, New York Unit, "Herb Garden Planning"19 Mar 1981 (Box 105, Folder 20)
    - Garden Club of Michigan, "Planning Small Gardens Today"9 Apr 1981 (Box 105, Folder 21)
    - American Women and Gardens, 1915-45 Conference, Wave Hill, Bronx, NY, "Landscape Architecture: A Women's Profession": correspondence, notes, and cassette tape recording16 Oct 1981 (Box 105, Folder 22-23)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, unititled21 Jan 1982 (Box 105, Folder 24)
    - Rye (NY) Garden Club, "Interesting Plant Material for Landscaping"2 Mar 1982 (Box 105, Folder 25)
    - Garden Club of Shelter Island (NY), "Landscaping with Native Material"22 May 1982 (Box 105, Folder 26)
    - Friends of Rock Hall, "Old Fashioned Gardens"2 Jun 1982 (Box 105, Folder 27)
    - Old Westbury Gardens, "The Evolution of Garden Design"3 Nov 1982 (Box 105, Folder 28)
    - Short Hills (NJ) Garden Club, "New Ideas for Old Gardens"19 Jan 1983 (Box 105, Folder 29)
    - Garden Club of America Horticulture Committee, "Designing with Unusual Plant Material"1 Feb 1984 (Box 105, Folder 30)
    - Millbrook (NY) Garden Club, "Designing with Unusual Plant Material"19 Jul 1984 (Box 105, Folder 31)
    - Nantucket Garden Club, "Landscape Design"22 Aug 1984 (Box 105, Folder 32)
    - Connecticut Valley and Hartford Garden Clubs joint meeting, "Landscaping Small Gardens"13 Nov 1984 (Box 105, Folder 33)
    - Garden Club of Princeton (NJ), "Landscaping Small Gardens"20 Nov 1984 (Box 105, Folder 34)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, "Planning and Designing Brownstone Landscapes"24 Feb 1985 (Box 105, Folder 35)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Clark Memorial Garden, "Concepts of Landscape Design"26 Oct 1985 (Box 105, Folder 36)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Clark Memorial Garden, "Concepts of Landscape Design," 1 Mar; and "A Landscape Course"26 Apr 1985 (Box 105, Folder 37)
    - Garden Club of Montclair (NJ), "New Trends in Landscape Planning"21 Apr 1986 (Box 105, Folder 38)
    - Brownstone Revival Committee, "Plantscaping"18 May 1986 (Box 105, Folder 39)
    - Short Hills (NJ) Home Garden Club, "Planning a New Look for Your Terrace"6 Oct 1986 (Box 105, Folder 40)
    - Clark Garden of the Brooklyn Botanic Garden, "Concepts of Landscape Design"1 Nov 1986 (Box 105, Folder 41)
    - Brooklyn Heights Garden Club, "Forcing Bulbs for Indoor Use"12 Nov 1986 (Box 105, Folder 42)
    - Brooklyn Union Gas, "City Gardens"26 Apr 1987 (Box 105, Folder 43)
    - West Virginia symposiumFeb 1988 (Box 105, Folder 44)
    - Brooklyn Hospital Auxiliary, "The Pleasures of a Summer Garden"17 May 1988 (Box 105, Folder 45)
    - W. Atlee Burpee Co.Nov 1988 (Box 105, Folder 46)
    - Rembrandt Club, "The Pleasures of Nature's Art in the Garden"Feb 1989 (Box 105, Folder 47)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, "Gardens for Children: Creating the Design"Feb 1989 (Box 105, Folder 48)
    - Orange and Duchess Garden Club, "Small Gardens-Design and Planting"18 Apr 1989 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Mohonk Garden Holiday, "Design and Unusual Plants for Small Gardens"27 Aug 1989 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Horticultural Alliance of the Hamptons (Long Island), "Design and Planting of a Small Garden"11 Mar 1990 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Ridgefield (CT) Garden Club, "Creative Plant Combinations"27 Nov 1990 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Four Virginia garden clubs, "Designing and Planting Your Property"16 Jan 1991 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Heights Garden Club, "Writing a Garden Book in 1991"9 Feb 1993 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Maymont Flower and Garden Show (Richmond, VA), "Design Ideas for Small Properties"19 Feb 1994 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Clark Garden of Brooklyn Botanic Garden, panel on landscape design1996 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - undated (Box 106, Folder 9-10)
  - Lecture handouts, general, undated
    - Advanced Landscape Course (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Berried Shrubs (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Birds (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Bulbs (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Children (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - City Gardens (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Color Throughout the Year (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Community Projects (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Containers (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Detail Landscape Design and Construction (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Detail Planting Notes (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - Evergreens (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - Flower Garden (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Flowering Trees (Box 107, Folder 14)
    - Garden Accessories/Features (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - Garden Maintenance (Box 107, Folder 16)
    - General Landscape Design (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - General Planting/Planting Fundamentals (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - Landscape Construction (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - Landscape Course outline (Box 107, Folder 20)
    - Landscape Fundamentals (Box 107, Folder 21)
    - Landscaping the Home Grounds (Box 107, Folder 22)
    - New Trends/What's New? (Box 107, Folder 23)
    - Outdoor Living Areas (Box 107, Folder 24)
    - Planning a Garden (Box 107, Folder 25)
    - Plant Composition (Box 107, Folder 26)
    - Plant Identification and Use (Box 107, Folder 27)
    - Planting Design (Box 107, Folder 28)
    - Principles of Landscape Design (Box 107, Folder 29)
    - Seashore (Box 107, Folder 30)
    - Shade, miscellaneous (Box 107, Folder 31)
    - Site Planning (Box 107, Folder 32)
    - Small Garden (Box 107, Folder 33)
    - Unusual/Interesting Plants (Box 107, Folder 34)
    - Water (Box 107, Folder 35)
    - Why Properties Should Be Planned (Box 107, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 107, Folder 37)
  - Illustrationsundated (Box 107, Folder 38)
- SERIES VIII. TEACHING
  - Acorn Garden Club (Washington, DC), Landscape Design Course spr 1971 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden
    - Spring 1937"Bulbs" (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Spring 1940"Planning the Garden" (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - 1945"Landscape Gardening" (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - 1947"Landscape Gardening" (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Spring 1948"Planning and Planting the Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Spring 1949"Planning and Planting the Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Spring 1950"Planning and Planting the Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Spring 1951"Landscape Gardening" (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Spring 1952"Plan Before You Plant" (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Spring 1953
      - "Flowering Shrubs and Trees" (Box 108, Folder 11)
      - "Plan Before You Plant" (Box 108, Folder 12)
      - "How to Lay Out a Suburban Plot" (Box 108, Folder 13)
    - Feb 1954"Landscaping Your Own Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 14)
    - 1955"Planning and Planting the Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 15)
    - 1956"Planning and Planting the Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 16)
    - 1957"Home Landscaping" (Box 108, Folder 17)
    - 1958"Home Landscaping" (Box 108, Folder 18)
    - 1959"Landscaping Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 19)
    - 1960"Landscaping Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 20)
    - Feb-Mar 1961"Plan and Plant Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 21)
    - 1962"Plan and Plant Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 22)
    - Mar 1967"Effective Garden Design" (Box 108, Folder 23)
    - Feb-Mar 1971"Plant and Plant Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 24)
    - Feb-Mar 1972"Plan and Plant Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 25)
    - Feb 1984"Brownstone Gardens" (Box 108, Folder 26)
    - "Landscaping a Brownstone Garden"
      - Mar 1986 (Box 108, Folder 27)
      - Nov 1986 (Box 108, Folder 28)
      - Feb 1987 (Box 108, Folder 29)
      - Apr 1987 (Box 108, Folder 30)
      - Feb 1988 (Box 108, Folder 31)
      - Oct 1988 (Box 108, Folder 32)
      - Feb 1989 (Box 108, Folder 33)
      - Oct-Nov 1989 (Box 108, Folder 34)
      - Feb 1990 (Box 108, Folder 35)
      - Feb-Mar 1991 (Box 108, Folder 36)
      - Feb-Mar 1992 (Box 108, Folder 37)
      - Feb-Mar 1993 (Box 108, Folder 38)
      - Mar 1994 (Box 108, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneousundated (Box 108, Folder 40)
  - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Clark Memorial Garden
    - Mar-Apr 1972"Plan and Plant Your Home Grounds" (Box 108, Folder 41)
    - Mar 1988"Landscape Design" (Box 108, Folder 42)
    - Fall 1989"Landscape Design for the Homeowner" (Box 108, Folder 43)
  - Connecticut College
    - Correspondence1945 (Box 108, Folder 44)
    - Landscape Gardening1943-44 (Box 108, Folder 45)
  - Cora Hartshorn Arboretum and Bird Sanctuary, Short Hills, NJ
    - Jan 1963?"Developing a Garden" (Box 108, Folder 46)
    - Jan-Feb 1964"Landscape Design" (Box 108, Folder 47)
    - Fall 1967"Garden Design" (Box 108, Folder 48)
    - Spr 1970"Gardening in the Shade" (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Spr 1983"Landscape Design" (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Delaware Federation of Garden Clubs, Flower Show SchoolOct 1964 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of Connecticut, Landscape Design WorkshopSep 1958 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of Maine, Landscape Design Study Course IApr 1976 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of Maryland, Landscape Design School
    - Course IIMar 1958 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Course VMar 1960 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Course INov 1965 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of Maryland, Landscape Design School
    - Course IVNov 1968 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Course IApr 1970 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Course IIIMar 1972 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Course IIIMay 1973 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Course IIIApr 1976 (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - Course IApr 1978 (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - Course IIIMar-Apr 1980 (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - undated (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of Maryland and National Capital Garden Club League
    - Landscape Design Study Course IIOct 1961 (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - Landscape Design Study Course IIIApr 1976 (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of New York State
    - Course for Flower Show Exhibitors and JudgesJan 1952 (Box 109, Folder 19)
    - School of Landscape Design
      - Spr 1957 (Box 109, Folder 20)
      - Course Ifall 1957 (Box 109, Folder 21)
      - Course VApr 1960 (Box 109, Folder 22)
      - Course VIOct 1960 (Box 109, Folder 23)
      - Course IIOct 1970 (Box 109, Folder 24)
      - Course IIIOct 1971 (Box 110, Folder 1)
      - Jan 1972 (Box 110, Folder 2)
      - Course IIISep 1981 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Garden Club Federation of Massachusetts, School of Landscape Design
    - Course INov 1961 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Course INov 1963 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Course IINov 1964 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Course IV spr 1969 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania, School of Landscape Design
    - Course IINov 1972 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Course IIIMay 1973 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Garden Club of America, Educational Symposium, "Planning the Small Garden"19-20 Nov 1952 (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Garden Club of Cranford (NJ), "Landscape Design"Feb 1972 (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Garden Club of Lawrence (NY)
    - Advanced Landscape CourseJan-Feb 1966 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Plant IdentificationOct 1966, Nov 1966, Jan 1967 (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Garden Club of New Jersey, School of Landscape Design
    - Course IVJan 1960 (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - Course IOct 1960 (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - Course IIOct 1964 (Box 110, Folder 16)
    - Course IIIMar 1965 (Box 110, Folder 17)
    - Course IIIMar 1967 (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - Course IIIOct 1969 (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - Greenwich (CT) Garden Center
    - "How to Plan and Plant Your Home Grounds" and "Landscape Fundamentals" spr 1974 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - "Landscape Design" and "Advanced Landscape Course"spr 1973, fall 1974 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Hillside Garden Club, Lynchburg, VA, "Landscape Design"
    - Mar 1973 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Fall 1973 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Millbrook (NY) Garden Club, Landscape Design Course, ? (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Morristown (NJ) Garden Club, Landscape Design CourseFeb 1972 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - National Council of State Garden Clubs, School of Landscape Design, Course IIIApr 1961, undated (Box 111, Folder 7-8)
  - New Canaan (CT) Garden Club, Landscape Design Course spr 1970 (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - New York Botanical Garden, Brownstone Gardens1984 (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - North Country Garden Club of Long Island
    - Landscape Design CourseJan-Feb 1963 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Advanced Landscape CourseFeb 1964 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Plant Identification and UseJan-Feb 1965 (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Rusticus Club (Bedford, NY), Landscape Design CourseJan-Feb 1970 (Box 111, Folder 14)
  - Rye (NY) Garden Club, Landscape Design Course
    - Jan-Feb 1960 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Jan-Feb 1962 (Box 111, Folder 16)
  - Scarsdale (NY) Adult School, Landscape Design Course
    - Fall 1949 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Fall 1967 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Fall 1968 (Box 111, Folder 19)
  - Stony Brook Garden Club (Princeton, NJ), Plant Identification and UseJan 1966 (Box 111, Folder 20)
  - Three Harbors Garden Club (Long Island, NY)
    - Landscape Design Course spr 1969 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - Advanced Landscape Coursespr 1970 (Box 111, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified notesundated (Box 111, Folder 23-25)
- SERIES IX. WRITINGS
  - Correspondence
    - General1953-85, undated (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Horticulture magazine1965-87 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - New York Sun1941, undated (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - New York Times1960-66, undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Articles
    - "The Approach to the Garden," The Brownstonercirca 1975 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Azalea Garden,New York Timescirca 1965 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - "Backyard Garden,"New York Times7 Apr 1946 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - "Between Two Gardens"circa 1941 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - "Broadleaved Evergreens for All-Year Effect," HorticultureOct 1968 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - "Charm Comes to a City Garden," New York Sun22 Feb 1941 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - "Founts of Color,"New York Times30 Mar 1958 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - "The Garden Life: James E. Cross of Long Island, New York," Garden Design, winter 1983 12 Correspondence, 1982-84
      - Drafts, notes, and text1982-83 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - "Garden Plans with a Purpose," The BrownstonerFeb 1975 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - "Guide for Novices,"New York Times19 Sep 1954 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - "A High Garden with a Bay View," New York Sun15 Feb 1941 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - "A Hillside Garden," Flower and Gardencirca 1976 (Box 112, Folder 17)
    - "How to Use Trees and Shrubs"undated (Box 112, Folder 18)
    - "Junipers are Useful," HorticultureNov 1966 (Box 112, Folder 19)
    - "Juvenile Delinquency in Brooklyn," Brooklyn Eagle13 Feb 1941 (Box 112, Folder 20)
    - "Landscape the Swimming Pool,"New York Times7 Sep 1961 (Box 112, Folder 21)
    - "Landscaping a Small Plot," Long Island Horticultural Society Bulletincirca 1972 (Box 112, Folder 22)
    - "Let's Have a Fruit Garden This Year," HorticultureMay 1975 (Box 112, Folder 23)
    - "Let's Have a Garden This Year"circa 1949 (Box 112, Folder 24)
    - "Litchfield Perennial Garden," New York Sun1 Mar 1941 (Box 112, Folder 25)
    - "Long Island Gardens," PaumanokJun 1973 (Box 112, Folder 26)
    - "Master Planner: A Landscape Architect Sets the Home Scene,"New York Times5 Feb 1961 (Box 112, Folder 27)
    - Multi-stem Trees,New York Timescirca 1966 (Box 112, Folder 28)
    - "Needle-leaved Evergreens for Many Purposes," HorticultureApr 1970 (Box 112, Folder 29)
    - "A New Approach,"New York Times18 Sep 1955 (Box 112, Folder 30)
    - "One-Color Plantings Will Accent a Garden,"New York Times1 Feb 1959 (Box 112, Folder 31)
    - "Perennial Trends: the Northeast,"New York Times10 Jan 1960 (Box 112, Folder 32)
    - "Plan for a Suburban Plot," New York Sun8 Feb 1941 (Box 112, Folder 33)
    - "Planned to Differ,"New York Times20 Mar 1955 (Box 112, Folder 34)
    - "Planning for Fall Garden Color,"New York Times15 Apr 1962 (Box 112, Folder 35)
    - "Planting a Garden Path," New York Suncirca 1941 (Box 112, Folder 36)
    - "Plot-Plan Guides New Home Landscaping,"New York Times5 Apr 1964 (Box 112, Folder 37)
    - "Railroad Ties in the Home Landscape," HorticultureOct 1974 (Box 112, Folder 38)
    - "A Remodeled Garden,"New York Timescirca 1960 (Box 112, Folder 39)
    - "Red Hook Housing Project," Alumnae Bulletin of the Smith College Graduate School of Architecture and Landscape ArchitectureMar 1941 (Box 112, Folder 40)
    - "Shade-Tolerant Plants Suit Problem Sites,"New York Times7 Apr 1957 (Box 112, Folder 41)
    - "Sunken Garden in the City,"New York Times18 Apr 1965 (Box 112, Folder 42)
    - Terrace Ideas,New York Timescirca 1964 (Box 112, Folder 43)
    - "Vines for Town," New York Sun5 Apr 1941 (Box 112, Folder 44)
    - "Wisteria," Flower and GardenApr 1966 (Box 112, Folder 45)
    - "Year-Round Color with Broadleaved Evergreens," HorticultureDec 1973 (Box 112, Folder 46)
  - Books
    - How to Plan and Plant Your Own Property, 1967
      - Published volume1967 (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - Clippings1967, undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Contract and royalty statements1965-84 (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence1957-85, undated (Box 113, Folder 4-6)
      - Illustrations
        - Listsundated (Box 113, Folder 7)
        - Detail plansundated (Box 113, Folder 8)
      - Information re gifts, purchases, and sales1967-82, undated (Box 113, Folder 9)
      - Interview on "The Jewish Home Show"1968 (Box 113, Folder 10)
      - Notesundated (Box 113, Folder 11-13)
      - Publicityundated (Box 113, Folder 14)
      - Typescriptundated (Box 113, Folder 15-20)
    - Small Gardens for City and Country: a guide to designing and planting your green spaces, ( Gardens for Brownstone and Brick)1978
      - Published volume1978 (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - Contract and royalty statements1976-89 (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence1973-85, undated (Box 114, Folder 3-4)
      - Illustrations
        - Lists and notesundated (Box 114, Folder 5)
        - Detail plansundated (Box 114, Folder 6-8)
      - Notesundated (Box 114, Folder 9)
      - Outlinesundated (Box 114, Folder 10)
      - Proposals1974, undated (Box 114, Folder 11-13)
      - Publicity1977-88, undated (Box 114, Folder 14)
      - Sales1979-90, undated (Box 114, Folder 15)
      - Typescriptundated (Box 114, Folder 16-17)
    - Designs for American Gardens (original title: Country Gardens)1991
      - Published volume1991 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, drafts, and notes1989-92, undated (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - Illustrations
        - General1991, undated (Box 115, Folder 3)
        - Detail plans, Chapters 1-14 (Box 115, Folder 4-17)
      - Outlines1989, undated (Box 115, Folder 18)
      - Publication party at Brooklyn Botanic Garden24 Nov 1991 (Box 115, Folder 19)
      - Publicity1992-93 (Box 115, Folder 20)
    - Garden Designs (Burpee American Gardening Series) (original title: Designed Gardens) 1991
      - Published volume1991 (Box 115, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence and notes1988-90, undated (Box 115, Folder 22)
      - Publicity and clippings1991-92 (Box 115, Folder 23)
      - Typescript (Box 115, Folder 24-25)
    - Book proposals
      - "Hudson River Valley Gardens"1974 (Box 115, Folder 26)
      - "Gardens for Grandparents"1978-80, undated
        - Correspondence, notes, and drafts (Box 115, Folder 27)
        - Illustrations by Helen Miller (Box 115, Folder 28)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS (BOXES)
  - I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
    - Awards
      - Liberty Hyde Bailey Medal1991 ASLA Fellow medal, 1978; Spirit of Life glass award, 1997 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Certificates and miscellaneous1961-99, undated (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Education
      - Cambridge School: miscellaneous sketches1934, undated (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - New York Chapter, American Society of Landscape Architects, Atelier: problemswinter 1938 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Houses: 94 Carswell St., Green Harbor, MA, plan of land1958 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - II. CLIENT FILES
    - Miscellaneous unidentified drawingsundated (Box 117, Folder 1-3)
  - V. PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Prints
      - Client files
        - Blum, Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Brown (Short Hills) (Box 118, Folder 1)
        - Curry, Donovan (William), Eristoff, Garden City (Box 118, Folder 2)
        - Ireys, Jackson, Love, Paley (Box 118, Folder 3)
        - Poor, Stim, Sturgis, Sulzberger (Box 118, Folder 4)
        - Timpson, Ward, Waters (Box 118, Folder 5)
        - Carlton Gardens (Box 119, Folder 1)
        - Heyes (Box 119, Folder 2)
        - Unidentified (Box 119, Folder 3-4)
  - VIII. TEACHING
    - Demonstration drawings and sketches, miscellaneousundated (Box 120, Folder 1-4)
  - IX. WRITINGS
    - Books
      - How To Plan and Plant Your Own Property: detail plans (Box 121, Folder 1-3)
      - Designs for American Gardens (Box 121, Folder 4)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS (FLAT FILE)
  - I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS (Map-case Flat file 27)
    - Education
      - Cambridge School
        - Thesis drawings
          - Originals-extremely fragile
          - Copies
      - Student sketches
  - VIII. TEACHING (Map-case Flat file 26)
    - Demonstration sketches and drawings
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS (ROLLED DRAWINGS)